<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kubernetes | Life of a Sysadmin]]></title>
  <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/categories/kubernetes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-12-21T12:06:35-06:00</updated>
  <id>https://yazpik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francisco Moctezuma]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes and Nginxplus demo]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/kubernetes-and-nginxplus-demo/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-27T12:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/kubernetes-and-nginxplus-demo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Load balancing a basic webbapp with nginxplus and kubernetes</h3>

<p>I think the best way to learn something new is doing in practice, theory is always good
but I&rsquo;m the kind of person who likes to do/try/test/ stuff and learn by doing/failing/changing.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also kind of new on kubernetes, and watching live-demos out-there is like I don&rsquo;t know nothing about cloud.
It seems everyday is a new tool that is better that the one created the day before to solve a problem.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really crazy how the cloud technology is in the pace right now, and sometimes I feel overwhelmed, but I&rsquo;m pretty sure I&rsquo;m not the only one with that feeling.
I decided get hands on, follow some demos out-there and add something else, so I started with this demo
, having kubernetes creating pods and loadbalancing them using nginxplus,</p>

<h4>The flow is the following</h4>

<ul>
<li>1.&ndash; NGINXplus load balancing a very simple webapp (configured on <a href="https://github.com/yazpik/lb-nginxplus/blob/master/backend.conf#L7-L13">backend.conf</a>)</li>
<li>2.&ndash; Console on top right is sending http load to the loadbalancer IP</li>
<li>3.&ndash; At the same time kubectl is talking with kubernetes API, changing replicas sets and deployments tags between containers</li>
<li>4.&ndash; Watch command of &ldquo;kubectl get pods&rdquo; to see how pods are being created and destroyed</li>
</ul>


<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/51XjbuS38ik" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>Ignore the broken english, I&rsquo;m still improving :)</p>

<p>I pretty much followed this guide from Kelsey Hightower</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_nPKCxtr7g4">Bringing Kubernetes to the Edge with NGINX Plus</a></li>
</ul>


<p>And official guides from Nginxplus</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nginx.com/products/application-load-balancing/">NGINX Plus as an Application Load Balancer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nginx.com/resources/admin-guide/load-balancer/">Admin Guide</a></li>
</ul>


<p>For this demo I&rsquo;ve created my own containers, and for that I found on <a href="http://quay.io">Quay.io</a> a phenomenal ally,
<a href="https://quay.io/repository/yazpik/spacemonkey">Spacemonkey container</a> was built to test kubernetes, changes between tags, releases, etc
So I can test rollout/rollback updates in kubernetes very easily,
 Another good thing is that the container is automatically created when I trigger a commit on Github due a Webhook configured on quay that is a really powerfull tool. <a href="https://docs.quay.io/guides/custom-trigger.html">(see Quay.io Webhooks)</a></p>

<p>To be more specific see this example of the Docker file being change between alpine and nginx versions <a href="https://github.com/yazpik/spacemonkey/commit/36f65cab94a0fcef4e629d45701fcc704cce423a#diff-3254677a7917c6c01f55212f86c57fbf">Hash </a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/yazpik/spacemonkey/commit/36f65cab94a0fcef4e629d45701fcc704cce423a#diff-3254677a7917c6c01f55212f86c57fbf"><img src="/images/dockerfie_ver1.jpg" title="&lsquo;DockerFile versioning&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<p>To finish this post I&rsquo;d like to bold this really cool feature on Quay, is called &ldquo;Quay Security Scanner&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s based on <a href="https://github.com/coreos/clair">Clair</a> Which is OpenSource.</p>

<p>It help you out to see what could be wrong with the packages you are using to built your container, so you will be aware if you are hitting a critical vulnerability or not.</p>

<p><a href="https://quay.io/repository/yazpik/spacemonkey/image/9be26d688d274b7ccaded0f5e12aba7f030a4949598faee05f85fa2b2800b6b5?tab=packages"><img src="/images/sec_scanner.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I have too much ideas to do with Kubernetes, I&rsquo;m still learning a lot, but I&rsquo;ll try to document my progress.</p>

<p>Stay tunned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes management dashboard]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/25/kubernetes-management-dashboards/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-25T19:50:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/25/kubernetes-management-dashboards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Yes there is a kubernetes dashboard.</h4>

<p>As I mentioned on my previous post I&rsquo;m using Vagrant + CoreOS to play with Kubernetes, so watching some demos on youtube always saw the nice dashboard but it took me a while to find out how to launch it and have a look to it.</p>

<p>There is a lot of documentation out there on how to reach the dashboard but actually didn&rsquo;t work for me, so I find this solution by myself, and I&rsquo;m not really sure if that is the right way, but it works.
Just need to find your kubernetes-dashboard pod on the kube-system namespace and do a port forwarding to 9090 port.</p>

<p>Get the kubernetes-dashboard pod name.
<code>bash
$ kubectl get pods -l k8s-app=kubernetes-dashboard --namespace=kube-system
</code>
Having a closer look to the kubernetes-dashboard pod to verify what port is actually listening, I use &ldquo;describe&rdquo; command which is always helpful
<code>bash
$ kubectl get describe pods  {kube-dashboard-podname}  --namespace=kube-system
</code>
Put attention to line #18 the Pod is using/listening on port 9090</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/yazpik/b00ffa49dbbb52c29b2976307ac3b870.js"></script>


<p>When you get the pod name just do port-fwd</p>

<p><code>bash
$ kubectl port-fwd {kube-dashboard-podname} 9090:9090 --namespace=kube-system
</code>
Here is an small asccinema recording on how I launch the dashboard.</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="https://asciinema.org/a/94128.js" id="asciicast-94128" async></script>


<p>And then you will have a clean and descriptive kubernetes dashboard running on <a href="http://localhost:9090">http://localhost:9090</a></p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/7389339/20637323/29410a1e-b34a-11e6-8506-b490d7586e83.png">https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/7389339/20637323/29410a1e-b34a-11e6-8506-b490d7586e83.png</a>" width="750" height="750" title="&lsquo;kube-dashboard01&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/7389339/20637330/47733854-b34a-11e6-814b-a45465747596.png">https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/7389339/20637330/47733854-b34a-11e6-814b-a45465747596.png</a>" width="750" height="750" title="&lsquo;kube-dashboard02&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Have fun out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with Kubernetes]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/23/getting-started-with-kubernetes/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-23T05:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/23/getting-started-with-kubernetes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><strong><em> Kubernetes  &ldquo;Fly my Pretties fly! &hellip; continue the research&rdquo;  </em></strong></h3>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/burns01.jpg" width="500" height="500" title="&lsquo;Fly my pretties&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>When I recently started to work with Docker and Kubernetes, this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m-H8PuweRVA">Simpson&rsquo;s Episode</a>   came to my mind,
Is very similar to me in the very beginning trying to deploy kubernetes.</p>

<p>I have spent my entire career as a Sysadmin and never wrote serious code,
you know as a Sysadmin we need to write some bash/ansible/perl scripts to help our-selfs and automate stuff, but things are changing now.</p>

<p>I have tried different ways to use it and test it out,
I had a OpenStack cluster ready so started playing with <a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Magnum">Magnum project</a>, it was not that hard and it really works, also tested how to do it with <a href="http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/openstack-kubernetes-more-choice-and-flexibility-for-developers/">Murano</a> and this deserve a larger post, unfortunately didn&rsquo;t documented my findings, but both are good options to run kubernetes on Openstack.</p>

<p>The problem with this projects is that I don&rsquo;t have the compute resources on my personal laptop to have an Openstack deployment and then kubernetes, so I started dig in a bit further on the way to have a kubernetes cluster up and running.</p>

<p>Found this guide from <a href="https://twitter.com/kelseyhightower">Kelsey Hightower</a>, <a href="https://github.com/kelseyhightower/kubernetes-the-hard-way">&ldquo;kubernetes the hardway&rdquo;</a> this helped me a lot to understand more what is all about all the
kubernetes components, the guide is based on GCE (Google Compute Engine), I did the installation on a different cloud provider, it&rsquo;s challenging but worked well for me.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Eventually I had to delete my instances running on the public cloud by obvious reasons, and I found another gnarly way to run kubernetes very easy, using
<a href="https://coreos.com/kubernetes/docs/latest/kubernetes-on-vagrant.html">Vagrant and CoreOS</a>, I have 16GB of RAM so it works great, so far running on a 4 nodes deployment, taking half of my compute power,
but still great, it already comes with heapster, kubedns, kube-dashboard, so this is a great way to learn how to manage a kubernetes cluster.</p>

<p>Also there is the option released on kubernetes 1.4 is <a href="http://kubernetes.io/docs/getting-started-guides/kubeadm/">kubeadm</a>
I haven&rsquo;t tested it out yet, but I&rsquo;ve heard is a good option to start on this kubernetes world.</p>

<h3>So you have kubernetes up and running.. now what?</h3>

<p>And we are back again with &ldquo;Mr. Burns fly my pretties&rdquo; mood, so just continue the research..</p>

<p>Is a good idea to have a look at this video from <a href="https://twitter.com/brendandburns">Brendan Burns</a> one of the kubernetes creators/founders, he is a former Google employee, now Microsoft owns his soul, he is a brilliant guy and I personal consider this is one of the best kubernetes technical explanations on internet.
I think is easier to understand the technical concepts having already a kubernetes deploy up and running and play around a bit,
that is why looks like I&rsquo;m starting backwards, but believe me is better to start in that way.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/WwBdNXt6wO4" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to quote/highlight some of his comments that are really valuable on this talk, among others.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;kubernetes is about decouple, decouple infrastructure&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;kubernetes is really about trying to provide a cluster a decoupling between you and the hardware ops and the kernel ops below you and the app ops you providing on top.
This also means is that your app containers view the world essentially as this sea of compute, and kubernetes means it takes any machine that you have available to use
they&rsquo;re entirely homogeneous every single machine you create in your fleet looks and feel exactly the same and they are indistinguishable so if one of them dies it
doesn&rsquo;t really matter all your application sees is there slightly less compute power available in the pool, is a really powerful abstraction it means I don&rsquo;t have to
worry about whats&rsquo;s going on in the OS, I don&rsquo;t have to ask someone to go and install a particular version of an OS, or a particular version of a library , and I do not have
to worry that somebody else is asking for an upgrade to a library that I also depend on, this decoupling of the application from the lower level compute on which it runs really
enables both the app developers and the people who run the machines, to live easier happier more decouple lives.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;kubernetes is really intended to be an online system a control system that is responsible not just for creating the world but actually maintaining and healing the world,
so again, if something goes wrong on the middle of the night, kubernetes can come along and actually fix and you never even get paged, that is a really powerful thing for developers
and sysadmins as well.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Have fun playing with kubernetes, I have documented some of my progress but is going to be a separate post&hellip;.
keep an eye here more to come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Modern Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/05/14/the-modern-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-14T21:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/05/14/the-modern-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Or the containerization of the cloud</h4>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kubernetes.jpeg" width="350" height="350" title="&lsquo;Kubernetes&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s right, Openstack and Containers are no enemies, and they are not fighting at all,
Those two technologies are a powerful combination bringing the best of &ldquo;two worlds&rdquo; but in different layers of the stack, maybe combining them does not make sense,but actually it really does.</p>

<p>Combining Openstack + Heat + Murano + Kubernetes it does sounds really complex but actually is becoming the opossite
I want to share with you an interesting article from OpenStack SuperUser website, during the kubernetes meetup in San Francisco, there was a live demo where it was demostrated how to deploy a <a href="http://kubernetes.io/">kubernetes</a> cluster in minutes with OpenStack and Murano.
<a href="http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/openstack-kubernetes-more-choice-and-flexibility-for-developers">http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/openstack-kubernetes-more-choice-and-flexibility-for-developers</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Also <a href="https://www.mirantis.com/">Mirantis</a> is collaborating with Google to have a better integration of Kubernetes with OpenStack.
<a href="https://www.mirantis.com/company/press-center/company-news/mirantis-collaborates-google-kubernetes-openstack-integration/">https://www.mirantis.com/company/press-center/company-news/mirantis-collaborates-google-kubernetes-openstack-integration/</a></p>

<p>Docker on Openstack Kubernetes, Craig Peters from Mirantis and Kit Merker from Google
<a href="https://openstacksummitmay2015vancouver.sched.org/event/57654c61f86cec3210d4d1065756409a">https://openstacksummitmay2015vancouver.sched.org/event/57654c61f86cec3210d4d1065756409a</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/coreos-logo.png" width="350" height="350" title="&lsquo;CoreOS&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The guys from <a href="https://coreos.com">CoreOS</a> have already take significant advantage, they are running several projects inside CoreOS, just to mention some, <a href="https://coreos.com/etcd/">Etcd</a>, <a href="https://coreos.com/blog/rocket/">Rocket</a>, <a href="https://coreos.com/using-coreos/clustering/">Fleet</a>, all of them written in <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a> language, helping to automatize and do things easy specially for developers delivering a powerful platform of containers.
This topic deserve a more descriptive post, and I&rsquo;ll try to do it soon, In the meantime If you are interested to try CoreOS with all the nice stuff give it a try to <a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a>, they have put togheter some vagrant scripts to deploy a 3 nodes CoreOs cluster.</p>

<p>And for the lucky ones that are going to OpenStack Summit in Vancouver, there is going to be plenty of talks covering containers, actually is a full day about it, just to have an idea what big is this Hot-Topic.</p>

<p>The containerization of the cloud is becoming huge, and is going to change how we understand the definition of the cloud these days.</p>

<p>See you in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Francisco Moctezuma</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCompute Re-Architecting the DataCenter]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/03/22/opencompute-re-architecting-the-datacenter/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T19:43:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/03/22/opencompute-re-architecting-the-datacenter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/opencompute.png" width="260" height="80" title="&lsquo;OpenCompute&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The OpenCompute Summit 2015 has just finished and there are some interesting talks from the top companies such Intel, Facebook, Linux, foundation, Microsoft and Rackspace.
For the ones that haven&rsquo;t heard about OpenCompute project, let me explain you with what is this about.</p>

<h4>From OpenCompute.org</h4>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>&ldquo;The Open Compute Project Foundation is a rapidly growing community of engineers around the world whose mission is to design and enable the delivery of the most efficient server, storage and data center hardware designs for scalable computing. We believe that openly sharing ideas, specifications and other intellectual property is the key to maximizing innovation and reducing operational complexity in the scalable computing space.&rdquo;</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Believe it or not this is a Facebook initiative to share the design of datacenter architecture with the intention to improve efficiency on servers, storage and also general datacenter overall infrastructure with smart and &ldquo;ecofriendly&rdquo; deployments.
I&rsquo;d say this is like an OpenSource project applied in hardware and is going to speed up the innovation on new hardware solutions.</p>

<p><img src="/images/opencomputeserver-750.jpg" width="360" height="140" title="&lsquo;OpenCompute Servers&rsquo;" >
<img src="/images/IODatacenter.jpg" width="360" height="140" title="&lsquo;IO Datacenter in Scottsdale&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Big names just joined to the OpenCompute project such as Apple and HP, So I believe in the next two years or so we will see a drastical change on Datacenter deployments as well as compute architecture, and we have to be ready to be competitive or much better be part of it, this is a good opportunity to join as one of the early adopters.</p>

<p>So Does anyone out there is already working on OCP hardware? I&rsquo;d be really interested to participate in something like that.</p>

<p>Most of the talks are already on OpenCompute youtube channel, I&rsquo;m gonna share some of the most remarkables, I&rsquo;ve watched so far.</p>

<h5>Jay Parik VP of Engineering at Facebook.</h5>

<p>This is one of the most interesting talks, Facebook is saving $2 Billion US Dls on the last three years applying a full stack optmization on the Datacenter, Software and Networking based on OpenCompute, But forget about the money one of the things it really matters is that the energy conservation they made is equals to power up 80,000 homes per year and carbon emission reduction equals to 95,000 cars also per year, I&rsquo;m not going to tell you the rest watch by yourself.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6QBrRT0VpgY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6QBrRT0VpgY</a></p>

<h5>Sam Ramji from Linux foundation</h5>

<p>He explain how OpenSource golden age can take place if we all collaborate in some way to create an OpenCloud platform, he made a point when Hortonworks went public with $1 Billion IPO using Hadoop and HDFS for Big Data, or Cloudera making $100M US Dls annual revenue to the other extreme when NTPd principal maintainer is making less than $20k per year, Well this is a must see talk.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uFfcCJcxlpk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uFfcCJcxlpk</a></p>

<h5>Mark Shutterworth from Canonical</h5>

<p>He really knows where the technology is moving, Mark showed on a live demo, an OpenStack Lab deployed with MAAS running a Ceph cluster on top of a JBOD (Just a Bunch of Disk) system provided by Quanta (OpenCompute provider), and the power of containers with Kubernetes (OpenSource container cluster orchestration) from Google. .. have a look.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a4P7lvIUc5M">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a4P7lvIUc5M</a></p>

<p>Greetings from Mexico!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
