<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: containers | Life of a Sysadmin]]></title>
  <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/categories/containers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-23T07:49:17-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://yazpik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francisco Moctezuma]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Modern Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/05/14/the-modern-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-14T21:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/05/14/the-modern-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Or the containerization of the cloud</h4>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/kubernetes.jpeg" width="350" height="350" title="&lsquo;Kubernetes&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s right, Openstack and Containers are no enemies, and they are not fighting at all,
Those two technologies are a powerful combination bringing the best of &ldquo;two worlds&rdquo; but in different layers of the stack, maybe combining them does not make sense,but actually it really does.</p>

<p>Combining Openstack + Heat + Murano + Kubernetes it does sounds really complex but actually is becoming the opossite
I want to share with you an interesting article from OpenStack SuperUser website, during the kubernetes meetup in San Francisco, there was a live demo where it was demostrated how to deploy a <a href="http://kubernetes.io/">kubernetes</a> cluster in minutes with OpenStack and Murano.
<a href="http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/openstack-kubernetes-more-choice-and-flexibility-for-developers">http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/openstack-kubernetes-more-choice-and-flexibility-for-developers</a></p>

<p>Also <a href="https://www.mirantis.com/">Mirantis</a> is collaborating with Google to have a better integration of Kubernetes with OpenStack.
<a href="https://www.mirantis.com/company/press-center/company-news/mirantis-collaborates-google-kubernetes-openstack-integration/">https://www.mirantis.com/company/press-center/company-news/mirantis-collaborates-google-kubernetes-openstack-integration/</a></p>

<p>Docker on Openstack Kubernetes, Craig Peters from Mirantis and Kit Merker from Google
<a href="https://openstacksummitmay2015vancouver.sched.org/event/57654c61f86cec3210d4d1065756409a">https://openstacksummitmay2015vancouver.sched.org/event/57654c61f86cec3210d4d1065756409a</a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/coreos-logo.png" width="350" height="350" title="&lsquo;CoreOS&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The guys from <a href="https://coreos.com">CoreOS</a> have already take significant advantage, they are running several projects inside CoreOS, just to mention some, <a href="https://coreos.com/etcd/">Etcd</a>, <a href="https://coreos.com/blog/rocket/">Rocket</a>, <a href="https://coreos.com/using-coreos/clustering/">Fleet</a>, all of them written in <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a> language, helping to automatize and do things easy specially for developers delivering a powerful platform of containers.
This topic deserve a more descriptive post, and I&rsquo;ll try to do it soon, In the meantime If you are interested to try CoreOS with all the nice stuff give it a try to <a href="https://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a>, they have put togheter some vagrant scripts to deploy a 3 nodes CoreOs cluster.</p>

<p>And for the lucky ones that are going to OpenStack Summit in Vancouver, there is going to be plenty of talks covering containers, actually is a full day about it, just to have an idea what big is this Hot-Topic.</p>

<p>The containerization of the cloud is becoming huge, and is going to change how we understand the definition of the cloud these days.</p>

<p>See you in Vancouver!</p>

<p>Francisco Moctezuma</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
