<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nginxplus | Life of a Sysadmin]]></title>
  <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/categories/nginxplus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-12-21T17:07:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>https://yazpik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francisco Moctezuma]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes and Nginxplus demo]]></title>
    <link href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/kubernetes-and-nginxplus-demo/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-27T12:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/kubernetes-and-nginxplus-demo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Load balancing a basic webbapp with nginxplus and kubernetes</h3>

<p>I think the best way to learn something new is doing in practice, theory is always good
but I&rsquo;m the kind of person who likes to do/try/test/ stuff and learn by doing/failing/changing.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also kind of new on kubernetes, and watching live-demos out-there is like I don&rsquo;t know nothing about cloud.
It seems everyday is a new tool that is better that the one created the day before to solve a problem.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s really crazy how the cloud technology is in the pace right now, and sometimes I feel overwhelmed, but I&rsquo;m pretty sure I&rsquo;m not the only one with that feeling.
I decided get hands on, follow some demos out-there and add something else, so I started with this demo
, having kubernetes creating pods and loadbalancing them using nginxplus,</p>

<h4>The flow is the following</h4>

<ul>
<li>1.&ndash; NGINXplus load balancing a very simple webapp (configured on <a href="https://github.com/yazpik/lb-nginxplus/blob/master/backend.conf#L7-L13">backend.conf</a>)</li>
<li>2.&ndash; Console on top right is sending http load to the loadbalancer IP</li>
<li>3.&ndash; At the same time kubectl is talking with kubernetes API, changing replicas sets and deployments tags between containers</li>
<li>4.&ndash; Watch command of &ldquo;kubectl get pods&rdquo; to see how pods are being created and destroyed</li>
</ul>


<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/51XjbuS38ik" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p>Ignore the broken english, I&rsquo;m still improving :)</p>

<p>I pretty much followed this guide from Kelsey Hightower</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_nPKCxtr7g4">Bringing Kubernetes to the Edge with NGINX Plus</a></li>
</ul>


<p>And official guides from Nginxplus</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.nginx.com/products/application-load-balancing/">NGINX Plus as an Application Load Balancer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nginx.com/resources/admin-guide/load-balancer/">Admin Guide</a></li>
</ul>


<p>For this demo I&rsquo;ve created my own containers, and for that I found on <a href="https://quay.io">Quay.io</a> a phenomenal ally,
<a href="https://quay.io/repository/yazpik/spacemonkey">Spacemonkey container</a> was built to test kubernetes, changes between tags, releases, etc
So I can test rollout/rollback updates in kubernetes very easily,
 Another good thing is that the container is automatically created when I trigger a commit on Github due a Webhook configured on quay that is a really powerfull tool. <a href="https://docs.quay.io/guides/custom-trigger.html">(see Quay.io Webhooks)</a></p>

<p>To be more specific see this example of the Docker file being change between alpine and nginx versions <a href="https://github.com/yazpik/spacemonkey/commit/36f65cab94a0fcef4e629d45701fcc704cce423a#diff-3254677a7917c6c01f55212f86c57fbf">Hash </a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/yazpik/spacemonkey/commit/36f65cab94a0fcef4e629d45701fcc704cce423a#diff-3254677a7917c6c01f55212f86c57fbf"><img src="/images/dockerfie_ver1.jpg" title="&lsquo;DockerFile versioning&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<p>To finish this post I&rsquo;d like to bold this really cool feature on Quay, is called &ldquo;Quay Security Scanner&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s based on <a href="https://github.com/coreos/clair">Clair</a> Which is OpenSource.</p>

<p>It help you out to see what could be wrong with the packages you are using to built your container, so you will be aware if you are hitting a critical vulnerability or not.</p>

<p><a href="https://quay.io/repository/yazpik/spacemonkey/image/9be26d688d274b7ccaded0f5e12aba7f030a4949598faee05f85fa2b2800b6b5?tab=packages"><img src="/images/sec_scanner.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I have too much ideas to do with Kubernetes, I&rsquo;m still learning a lot, but I&rsquo;ll try to document my progress.</p>

<p>Stay tunned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
