<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: openstack | Life of a Sysadmin]]></title>
  <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/categories/openstack/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-12-21T14:03:22-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://yazpik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francisco Moctezuma]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Learnt OpenStack by failing]]></title>
    <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/09/09/how-i-learn-openstack/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-09T21:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2016/09/09/how-i-learn-openstack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><strong><em> Demotivation of Innovation </em></strong></h3>

<p><img src="/images/lops/cloud-domination.jpg" width="650" height="550" title="&lsquo;Our idea of Cloud computing back in 2014&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Last night having a beer with my friend <a href="http://arturoochoa.wordpress.com">Arturo Ochoa</a> we were talking about what really motivates you to innovate and/or create something that help fixing problems.
We were not sure what is all about,
but we felt same way, when you are doing it, you always think whatever you are implementing it does really suck, ..maybe not creating something new, your skills are not enough, etc. etc
But the reality is that maybe nobody is doing anything about it, and find yourself as the only one with you poor skills trying to do something different.
We tent to underestimate our efforts in a really bad way, and maybe that stop us going to the next level&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;d like to share my story, how I learnt by doing and I&rsquo;ll say trying to simplifying things and solving existing problems using OpenStack as a platform.</p>

<p>-Back in 2013 on my former employer I had plenty of time due I got some storage skills on my position, as a Sr Storage Engineer at that time being. Not too much automated stuff but enough to give me time to learn something else.
Bash, Perl, ssh-keys and one big xls file involved here :)</p>

<p>-I started testing Openstack (Grizzly) and Eucaliptus on my own laptop but didn&rsquo;t work at all.</p>

<p>-I heard some guys from the same company but in Slovakia, were trying to connect Netapp as backend storage on an OpenStack test cloud. &ndash; I offered my help but I got rejected.</p>

<p>-So I continued on my self learning pace.</p>

<p>-One of my previous managers wanted a solution to store files on the internal network, I offered him some help and he
gave me 3 very old servers and one disk array. Just for the records &ndash; <strong><em>never finished what he really wanted.</em></strong></p>

<p>-Managed to build one server from 3 I got, a very old Proliant G4 with 12GB of RAM and 2 CPUs at 2.4GHz, and a Disk array with 5 failed disks of 12, and suddenly <strong>Nazgul01</strong> was born.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/lab02.jpg" width="350" height="550" title="&lsquo;lab&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>-I felt like I have something here</strong></p>

<p>-Got access to the electronic Junk and trash, hardware listed to be donated by my previous employer.</p>

<p>-In the meantime annoyed my co-workers with really noise old and dusty hardware from the cracks.</p>

<p>-For some reason big companies tent to underestimate a &ldquo;barrio bajo&rdquo; guy with roedor skills, to find usable hardware
So one idiot from networking team, throw to the trash a Cisco Catalyst switch, I took it, test it, configured and failed configuring it like ten times, the idiot was not longer an idiot, and I realized something was wrong with the switch. my intern number 2 managed to rebuilt the OS for me, and it worked very nicely supporting jumbo frames&hellip; so intern wins, and I was just another idiot.</p>

<p>-Also from the trash, found 4xG5 Proliants, lead to built 3 &ldquo;<em>decents</em>&rdquo; servers using the parts of those 4.</p>

<p><strong>-I felt, invincible.. and dusty</strong></p>

<p>-Realized I needed some extra help, my Linux skills were not as good as I thought anymore, due I spent a lot of time playing with a SAN appliance.
So I sent an email to my friend <a href="https://karkul.github.io">Ramon Morales</a>, if he would like to join me, and I got an email from him five minutes later with a &ldquo; <strong>let&rsquo;s fucking do it!</strong> &rdquo;  or something like that.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/lab03.jpg" width="350" height="550" title="&lsquo;lab&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>-We spent several days trying to Install Openstack in 3 nodes not even configure it.
One month mark passed and we started to think this Openstack thing was a myth because we failed and failed
and&hellip;&hellip;.failed.</p>

<p><strong>So we started to read manuals&hellip;.</strong></p>

<p>-Like two months later, we were able to spin up our first instance running CirrOS.
and <strong>Booooom</strong> an inovation explosion just happened.</p>

<p><strong>-We felt unstopable</strong></p>

<p>We can even were able to launch virtual instances from a mobile phone, using a VPN, see images below.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/cloudportal_movil.png" width="650" height="400" title="&lsquo;lab&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/cloudportal_movil2.png" width="650" height="450" title="&lsquo;lab&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>-We have had a lot of ideas, we learnt as we use it, that platform was awesome&hellip; with a lot of patches and networking hacks but awesome,
none of us managed vmware previously, also we didn&rsquo;t understand the disadvantages against vmware at that time.</p>

<p>-I attended a meeting with the Innovation department, excited and wanted to show them our little monster.</p>

<p>When a big company has a solution for years, and sell that solution in millions of dollars,
and always have been successful, everything is running flawlessly..
<strong>Why other platform that was buggy, without support, complex, and SAP is not certifiying your crap could have place in this company?</strong></p>

<p>Basically that was the output from that meeting&hellip;</p>

<p>-You can be really demoralized after a meeting like that, but sometimes I&rsquo;m stubborn as fuck&hellip;
At the end of October 2014, We ended up releasing our very first buggy version of OpenStack based on Juno.  <strong>CATRINA</strong> was born..</p>

<p>We offered some instances for Trial &amp; Demo, -Hey free virtual instances with no internet access for free!
None, nadie, nobody&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>-Some sort of support</strong></p>

<p>A young Entrepreneur &ndash;<a href="https://twitter.com/jarocho_1">Francisco Fuentes</a> from the management, saw something on our idea, and supported us with four more servers, that we can use on our little monster as compute nodes,
Then Fuentes joined SAP team as the new manager, and suggested them to use our platform for learning SAP porpuses.
We started serving cloud services for SAP, with the power of OpenStack, very easy and fast, performance was really good,
nobody complained they never thought their instances were running on a test platform managed from some linux hippies.
We ran SAP Business Object, SAP Solman, SAP W-something, and believe or not <strong>SAP HANA.</strong></p>

<p>Our next releases were</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>TYRION</strong> &ndash; A clever version with automated bootstrapping, and PXE.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>MUTANT</strong> Using CEPH with a crappy disk array built from the junk as well, but it was running great.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And we started to make some noise back then,
We got a meeting with some of the high level managers, we showed them our monster, and&hellip; <strong>we didn&rsquo;t meet their expectactions by far.</strong></p>

<p>They were thinking on an enhanced version of VMware, and we failed to explained them in a non technical way why we think this technology could help the company saving money and time.</p>

<p>They said we need a TCO, Bussines Cases and so on, &hellip;again believe or not, we built a TCO and a BC with our poor financial skills, even a freaking promotional video.
<img src="/images/lops/produccion1.jpg" width="500" height="500" title="&lsquo;Video&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/produccion2.jpg" width="500" height="500" title="&lsquo;Video&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>But for some reason it wasn&rsquo;t not enough, here are the results</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/SF5rz2rdBLs" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<h4>OpenStack Summit in Vancouver 2015 &ndash; Cloud or die.</h4>

<p>So we took our savings, booked the cheapest hotel we found in Vancouver downtown, bought flight tickets, got Canadian VISA approved, and boooom we were in Canada with no support from our employer.</p>

<p>We learnt a lot about new concepts, new technologies, we met interesting and smart people, we had fun, and even <strong>Ramon got the OpenStack certification by Redhat</strong>, I tried but failed.. again  :) , just fun so we realized after that trip, this is the new thing, not Openstack but Cloud and containers revolution.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/vancouver2.jpg" width="600" height="600" title="&lsquo;Vancouver&rsquo;" ></p>

<h5>Spread the word!</h5>

<p>We were invited to gave some talks on universities, ITESM, BUAP, Universidad Veracruzana, and we organized a SysAdminDay in our company.
By the end of 2015 one year later of Catrina creation,
We were considered by the management to attend the <strong>OPENTELEKOM Cloud</strong> technical talk in Budapest, Hungary. <strong>(we no longer use our own money to pay for beers on that trip)</strong> ,
OTC is a Deustche Telekom initiative to build a public cloud based on OpenStack to offer in the European Market.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/frankfurt3.jpg" width="650" height="650" title="&lsquo;Frankfurt&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Also taking advantage of the long trip we had the opportunity to show a demo in Frankfurt, Germany, to some of the Senior Cloud engineers, pretty much how we managed to run OpenStack as an Enterprise private cloud, supporting all SAP toys, SAP HANA, Big Data with Hadoop, our progress with OpenStack + VMWare, and Docker.
we were able to launch a Hadoop cluster in just a few minutes, as I described on a previous post <a href="https://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/11/16/bigdata-as-a-service/">Big Data as a Service</a> , that was by the end of the 2015.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/frankfurt.jpg" width="500" height="500" title="&lsquo;Frankfurt&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>We went back to Mexico with a good feedback from Germany and Hungary, and we were proud of what we have achieved so far, but not enough for us.</p>

<p>We always asked ourselfs</p>

<p><strong>Why as a company, as a country, we need to wait the innovation from USA, Europe or Asia? and not step up first, even when you have the resources and the customers&hellip;.</strong></p>

<p>So this OpenStack lab built from the junk, in less than two years took us to three different countries and a new continent for us.
We were wrong in so many levels, and failed to explain to the management our vision, perhaps.</p>

<p>The only thing we were not wrong, was about to learn new things and have fun by doing it, push our own limits, and do not underestimate what we built, at the end, no one else was doing it on our small environment.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lops/lab04.png" width="650" height="650" title="&lsquo;Lab04&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BigData As A Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/11/16/bigdata-as-a-service/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-16T19:22:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2015/11/16/bigdata-as-a-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>A complete elastic Hadoop cluster with OpenStack + Sahara in 15 minutes</h3>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/bigdata.gif" width="650" height="650" title="&lsquo;Dilbert Data Accuracy&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Hi there&hellip; I haven&rsquo;t been here for a while for several reasons, that includes a super hyperactive baby girl and a lot of effort building an Enterprise class ready Private cloud based in OpenStack using a tremendous set of new technologies, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software-defined_storage" title="SDS">SDS</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software-defined_networking" title="SDN">SDN</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing#Infrastructure_as_a_service_.28IaaS.29" title="Iaas">IaaS</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing#Infrastructure_as_a_service_.28IaaS.29" title="PaaS">PaaS</a>, <a href="https://www.docker.com/" title="Docker">Containers</a>, <a href="http://go.sap.com/solution/in-memory-platform.html">Hana</a> and now <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data">BigData</a>.
the good thing is, working along with a talented guy as <a href="https://twitter.com/karkull" title="Karkull">Ramon Morales</a> things are easier to do, brainwork becomes a hobbie on a playground and innovation just flows.
but anyway let&rsquo;s jump on the BigData stuff.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of our DBA&rsquo;s ask us for a Linux instance on the OpenStack cloud, first questions from me was, purpose ? , so he wanted to try and learn about Hadoop, so I started to look if there was an image ready for it or start to build one from scratch and meet the Hadoop pre-requisites, at the end the DBA won&rsquo;t install the Hadoop platform, that will be the sysadmins or Devops :)
So I was on an interesting situation, reading in deep I found a pararell world about DataProcessing and BigData, and then project <a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Sahara/">Sahara</a> formerly known as Savanna, immediatly I get caught on it.</p>

<p>But WHAT IS SAHARA?</p>

<p>Sahara began life as an Apache 2.0 project and is now an OpenStack integrated project, Sahara enables the fast provisioning and easy management of Hadoop clusters on Openstack, mainstream Hadoop distributions and elastic data processing (EDP) capability similar to Amazon Elastic MapReduce (EMR).</p>

<p>So here are basic steps to add Sahara on an existing OpenStack deployment.</p>

<p>On the OpenStack control Node (ubuntu)
I started searching the packages for Sahara first, didn&rsquo;t break anything on control nodes :)</p>

<pre>
$ sudo apt-cache search sahara
</pre>


<p>That gets me sahara, python-saharaclient, and openstack-dashboard, I already have the dashboard installed, so just needed to install sahara package and the python-saharaclient.</p>

<pre>
$ sudo apt-get install sahara python-saharaclient
</pre>


<p>Find out the sahara configuratin file, default path is /etc/sahara, there are some samples placed in the sahara directory, you can use the basic sample or generate a new one with</p>

<pre>
$ sudo tox -e genconfig
</pre>


<p>That will get you a sahara.conf file, you can modify basic parameters, such as Networking(Neutron), Database(Mysql), Message systems(Rabbit), Identity(Keystone), for a reference guide please see: <a href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/sahara/userdoc/configuration.guide.html" title="Sahara config guide">Sahara Configuration Guide</a></p>

<p>Then a Database Schema for Shara is needed, you can create it as follows (on an existing empty database)</p>

<pre>
$ sudo sahara-db-manage --config-file /etc/sahara/sahara.conf upgrade head
</pre>


<p>my db connection string on sahara.conf file is</p>

<p>```bash sahara.conf (snippet)
connection=mysql://admin:ridiculouspass@localhost:3306/saharadb</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Great, we have a database schema for Sahara, please make sure Database hosts is reacheable by sahara node and neutron management network.</p>

<h5>Keystone configuration</h5>

<p>This is another essencial part for sahara to be accesible in the OpenStack dasboard and for python sahara client to work properly we need to add sahara on keystone catalog</p>

<p>As keystone admin, create the service &ldquo;sahara&rdquo; as data_processing type</p>

<pre>
(keystone_admin)# keystone service-create --name sahara --type data_processing \
    --description "Sahara Data Processing"
</pre>


<p>Next create the endpoint and define the access + Region</p>

<pre>
(keystone_admin)# keystone endpoint-create --service sahara --region RegionOne \
    --publicurl "http://172.16.0.2:8386/v1.1/%(tenant_id)s" \
    --adminurl "http://10.0.0.2:8386/v1.1/%(tenant_id)s" \
    --internalurl "http://192.168.0.2:8386/v1.1/%(tenant_id)s"
</pre>


<p>Make sue you match the admin, public and internal network on the new service, you can verify the current endpoints with</p>

<pre>
(keystone_admin)# keystone endpoint-list
</pre>


<h5>Configure Firewall to Allow Sahara service traffic</h5>

<p>Add an INPUT rule allowing TCP traffic on port 8386, and restart iptables</p>

<pre>
-A INPUT -p tcp -m multiport --dports 8386 -j ACCEPT
</pre>


<p>Start Sahara service</p>

<pre>
    service sahara-all start
</pre>


<p>Also you can setup Sahara on a virtual python environment, I didn&rsquo;t try that, but can be found here
<a href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/sahara/userdoc/installation.guide.html#to-install-into-a-virtual-environment">Sahara Virtualenv</a></p>

<p>There are also advanced configurations for Sahara, you can find them here
<a href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/sahara/userdoc/advanced.configuration.guide.html">Sahara Advanced configuration</a></p>

<p>That is a high level steps for Sahara in OpenStack, so once we have them all and you can see Data Processing panel on Horizon, so from here 15 minutes can start to count to create a cutting-edge fresh hadoop cluster.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/01_Hadoop.png" width="200" height="600" title="" ></p>

<p>Then there are some pre-configured images for Hadoop vanilla plugin, you can download them from here
<a href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/sahara/userdoc/vanilla_plugin.html">Vanilla Plugin</a></p>

<p>And it can be easily upload to glance, then to the Data processing image registry
<img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/02_hadoop.png" width="600" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p>Sahara makes it possible to create nodes and cluster templates, You can mix and match roles for a node, also you can scale out your cluster as many or few nodes you need.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/03_hadoop.png" width="600" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/05_hadoop.png" width="400" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p>Because I couldn&rsquo;t say it better than mirantis.com</p>

<p>&ldquo;Manually creating a Hadoop cluster on OpenStack requires spinning up instances, installing Hadoop on each instance, configuring the instances to work together, specifying the namenode, jobtracker, tasktrackers, and any storage nodes, and configuring each of hundreds, or even thousands, of nodes. Why spend all that time on manual configuration — with the possibility of human error — when you can use Sahara to specify node characteristics and roles, click to deploy, and access a individual or multiple robust, stable Hadoop clusters in parallel with minimal delay?&rdquo;</p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/07_hadoop.png" width="600" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p>Also the Hadoop cluster can be scalable with no pain, so you can save time
when it comes to create and configure new nodes, only simply add node types by the OpenStack Sahara user interface</p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/11_hadoop.gif" width="600" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p>And voila you have a fresh Elastic Hadoop deployment ready in just a few minutes.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/10_hadoop.png" width="500" height="200" title="" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/09_hadoop.png"></p>

<p><img src="/images/Hadoop_Post/08_hadoop.png" width="600" height="300" title="" ></p>

<p>So this is pretty much everything about the installation of Hadoop on OpenStack (Juno)
Next post We&rsquo;ll run a job on the cluster, stay tunned :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual Machine migration from VMware to OpenStack/KVM]]></title>
    <link href="http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/virtual-machine-migration-from-vmware-to-openstack/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T18:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://yazpik.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/virtual-machine-migration-from-vmware-to-openstack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a quick and easy guide to migrate VMWare VM&rsquo;s to OpenStack (KVM) using Redhat Enterprise 6.5</p>

<h4>Install virt-v2v</h4>

<p>The virt-v2v command converts virtual machines from a foreign hypervisor to run on KVM, managed by libvirt.</p>

<pre>
# yum install virt-v2v
</pre>


<p>Next step is create an xml file for the pool and indicate the storage path, I created a very simple xml file, like this one:</p>

<p>```xml pool.xml</p>

<p><pool type="dir"></p>

<pre><code>    &lt;name&gt;virtimages&lt;/name&gt;
    &lt;target&gt;
      &lt;path&gt;/home/images&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/target&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></pool></p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Create an storage pool based on the xml file with virsh command and refeer the xml file</p>

<pre>
# virsh pool-create --file pool.xml
</pre>


<p>List the storage pool, &ldquo;virtimages&rdquo; pool is refering to the path given on the xml file which is /home/images</p>

<!-- more -->




<pre>
# virsh pool-list
</pre>


<p>``` vim virsh output</p>

<h2>Name                 State       Autostart</h2>

<p>virtimages           active       no
```</p>

<p>Create a .netrc file with ESX credentials, where the machine that you want to convert is hosted.</p>

<pre>
machine ESXi login root password s3cretitos
</pre>


<p>Convert the VMware VM to KVM, the virtual machine has to be stopped before to proceed with this, go to Virtual center and turn the VM off.</p>

<pre>
# virt-v2v -ic esx://(ESX IP address or name) -o libvirt -os (Storagepool) (VMname)
</pre>




<pre>
# virt-v2v -ic esx://ESXi/?no_verify=1 -o libvirt -os virtimages Trusty_test_CLON
</pre>


<p><code>bash virt-v2v output
Trusty_test_Trusty_test: 100% [===============================]D 0h04m25s
virt-v2v: Trusty_test_CLON configured without virtio drivers.
</code>
On my example I worked on a diferent server with libvirt, do not recommend to do this on a Openstack computer node running libvirt, so I performed this steps on a different node.</p>

<p>Convert the recent generated RAW image to qcow2 using qemu.</p>

<pre>
qemu-img convert -f raw -O qcow2 images/Trusty_test_Trusty_test  images/Trusty_exported.qcow2
</pre>


<p>Let&rsquo;s play with Glance, adding/importing the new image into image repository, the .qcow2 image generated by qemu is the one that we need to point to be imported in glance.</p>

<pre>
glance image-create --name Ubuntu_exported --is-public False --container-format bare --disk-format qcow2 < Trusty_exported.qcow2
</pre>


<p>Go to Openstack dashboard and create a new instance based on the new imported image from ESX, which in this case is “Trusty_exported.qcow2”, make sure you match the flavor with the sizing used on ESX, I tried a couple of flavors and then voila the OS was able to boot.
So you will be able to test the Exported/Imported VM from VMWare to Openstack/KVM.</p>

<h4>References</h4>

<p><a href="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization/3.0/html-single/V2V_Guide/index.html#chap-V2V_Guide-Installing_virt_v2v">https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization/3.0/html-single/V2V_Guide/index.html#chap-V2V_Guide-Installing_virt_v2v</a></p>

<p><a href="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_for_Servers/2.2/html/Administration_Guide/virt-v2v-scripts.html">https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_for_Servers/2.2/html/Administration_Guide/virt-v2v-scripts.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
